<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Lords Justices and Council. Mich. Armach. C. Granard. Whereas we are informed that divers of his Majesties subjects in several parts of this kingdom, being possessed with strange fears &amp; groundless jealousies, have frequently of late deserted their own dwelling houses, ...</title>
            <author>Ireland. Lords Justices and Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1685</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B24849</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I981</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.21.f.12[14]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide G.6022[12]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R223025</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225839</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886328</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886328</idno>
            <idno type="VID">186586</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B24849)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186586)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C5:2[14]; C23:1[12])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Lords Justices and Council. Mich. Armach. C. Granard. Whereas we are informed that divers of his Majesties subjects in several parts of this kingdom, being possessed with strange fears &amp; groundless jealousies, have frequently of late deserted their own dwelling houses, ...</title>
                  <author>Ireland. Lords Justices and Council.</author>
                  <author>Granard, Arthur Forbes, Earl of, 1623-1696.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2] leaves.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Benjamin Tooke, printer to the Kings most excellent Majesty; and are to be sold by Andrew Crook at the printing-house on Ormonde-Key, and Samuel Helsham at the Colledge-Arms in Castle-Street.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1685]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Title from caption and opening lines of text.</note>
                  <note>At end of text: Given at the Council-Chamber in Dublin, the 24th day of July. 1685.</note>
                  <note>Against unlawful assemblies. Cf. Steele.</note>
                  <note>Arms 186.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  James II, 1685-1688 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  History --  1649-1775 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  Politics and government --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:186586:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               </figure> BY THE Lords Juſtices AND COUNCIL.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>Mich. Armach. C. Granard.</signed>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>HEREAS We are informed that di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers of His Majeſties Subjects in ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral parts of this Kingdom, being poſſeſſed with ſtrange fears &amp; ground<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs jealouſies, have frequently of late deſerted their own dwelling Houſes, and have reſorted either to Caſtles or other places of Strength, or into the Fields or Woods in the night-time, under colour of ſecuring themſelves from dangers, which (conſidering the quiet and peaceable condition this Kingdom is in) there is no reaſon for them to apprehend; We think fit hereby to Require and Command all His Majeſties ſubjects in this Kingdom, to forbear all unlawful meetings in the night-time, and other diſorderly aſſembling of themſelves together, and that they do quietly &amp; peaceably demean themſelves, following
<pb facs="tcp:186586:2"/> their ſeveral Callings and Employments, and not forſaking their own Habitations, upon pretence of any ſuch groundleſs Fears or Apprehenſions; as they will anſwer the contrary at their perils; We being reſolved, by His Majeſties Authority where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with We are intruſted, ſufficiently to provide for the Security and Preſervation of all His Majeſties Subjects, both in their Perſons, Eſtates, and Poſſeſſions, according to the Laws of this Realm, which We ſhall take care to ſee duely executed, for the Safety and Protection of all His Majeſties faithful and obedient Subjects, and the Terror and Puniſhment of all Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſturbers of their Peace and Quiet.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at the Council-Chamber in <hi>Dublin,</hi>
                  </hi> 
                  <date>
                     <hi>the 24th day of <hi>July.</hi>
                     </hi> 1685.</date>
               </dateline> 
               <hi>GOD Save the KING.</hi>
               <signed>Franc. Dublin. Roſcommon. Longford. Bleſinton. Char. Feilding. John Keating. He. Hene. John Davys. Ric. Reynell. Rob. Hamilton.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Dublin, Printed by Benjamin Tooke, Printer to the Kings Moſt Excellent Majeſty; And are to be Sold by Andrew Crook at the Printing-houſe on Ormonde-Key, and Samuel Helſham at the Colledge-Arms in Caſtle-Street.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
